<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[A portfolio of a business analyst]]></description><link>https://ZahraSadjadi.github.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 09:58:56 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Loan Approval Prediction]]></title><description><![CDATA[Description:
This project applies machine learning models to predict loan approval, utilizing a dataset that contains details like gender…]]></description><link>https://ZahraSadjadi.github.io/loan-prediction/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://ZahraSadjadi.github.io/loan-prediction/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt;
This project applies machine learning models to predict loan approval, utilizing a dataset that contains details like gender, marital status, education, and employment status to determine loan eligibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skills:&lt;/strong&gt;
Predictive modeling, data preprocessing, machine learning, statistical analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hard skills:&lt;/strong&gt;
Python, Scikit-Learn, Pandas, NumPy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt;
Developed a model capable of predicting loan approval status with high accuracy, aiding in the decision-making process for loan issuances.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more detailed insights, you can view the original project on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaggle.com/code/zahrasadjadi/loan-approval-prediction-as-my-school-project&quot;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Forecasting US GDP Growth Rate]]></title><description><![CDATA[Description: This project focuses on predicting the US GDP growth rate using the ARIMA model, applying time series analysis to understand…]]></description><link>https://ZahraSadjadi.github.io/us-gdp-forcast/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://ZahraSadjadi.github.io/us-gdp-forcast/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; This project focuses on predicting the US GDP growth rate using the ARIMA model, applying time series analysis to understand and forecast economic trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skills:&lt;/strong&gt; Time series forecasting, economic modeling, statistical analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hard skills:&lt;/strong&gt; Python, ARIMA modeling, Pandas, statsmodels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt; Successfully developed a predictive model that forecasts US GDP growth rates, providing valuable insights for economic planning and strategy.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details, you can explore the original project on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaggle.com/code/zahrasadjadi/forecasting-us-gdp-growth-rate-with-arima-model&quot;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>